Andy Chen

Rich experience in full-stack software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team.

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

EXPERIENCE

Minted LLC, San Francisco — Senior Software Engineer March 2019 - PRESENT

- Work at software architecture team to improve internal tooling and speed up automation pipelines by 5 times.
- Author internal protobuf development process from building, compiling, testing to deploying, distribution and migration, mainly in leverage GNU make, shell scripts and dockers.
- Maintain and build kafka python client library, beam/flink pipeline.

<u>Blockchain Node Service Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Founder and Project Lead Developer* July 2018 - PRESENT

- Leverage Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distribute stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decreased responding time by 50%.
- Develop a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

Bodhi Project, San Mateo— *Senior Software Engineer* May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Refactored the whole React UI library from redux to mobX architecture in 4 weeks and successfully initiated the migration from electron-based to browser-based DApp which ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2 times.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex solidity smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the development process.
- Built the prototype of ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Mateo — *Lead Engineer turned Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

 Co-authored whitepaper, designed and developed the end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month. Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Backend: **RESTful/GraphQL Beam/Flink, grpc/protobuf**express.js, MongoDB/SQL,
Next.js, SSR, SEO, JWT

DevOps: NPM/nexus,
Docker/K8S, TravisCI/Jenkins,
CircleCI, Truffle, AWS CSAA,
GNU make, unix shell

Languages: Javascript, **Nodejs**, **Golang**, Python, **Solidity, bash**

Front-End: html/css/sass, Javascript, **React/Redux**, **MobX**, Gulp, **Webpack**, **RWD**

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

use-form-react, a react form hook made building form use in any react app.

mern, open source mern stack boilerplate repo and with over 1K downloads and clones.

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update and
improve testing environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

- Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Developed an ERC-20 compatible VentureCoin(VCN) token and successfully launched a 3-month crowd-sale in November 2017.

Yeah Education Group, Berkeley — Lead Engineer Dec. 2015 - April 2017

 Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API. Successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

<u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Web Developer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned a full satisfaction rate from clients.

EDUCATION

<u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental). Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

<u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Startup Hero* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Grown <u>venode</u> project into <u>BNS</u> and graduated as top 3 of "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day. Completed full Hero Training Program and was nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper.

PROJECTS

<u>Leptin</u> — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and built a whole cryptocurrency in Nodejs with leveraging the power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain implementing Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

Etherbrite — An Eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register and check-in.

HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - **1st place of Uber Challenge** for building <u>Teleport</u>, an advertisement site that connects customers and business.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall**[2015] for building

Connect, a radio player

controlled with Myo gesture

controller.

MENTORSHIP/BLOG

Distributed Tech Salon

authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web dev, smart contract, DevOps and Arc. design topics.

<u>Group</u> on Github I founded virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland

Reactathon, 2017 Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization